Last orders, please.
打烊前最后点餐了
- Shaun.
- Yeah?
-肖恩
-什么事?
- Do you see what I'm saying?
- Yeah, totally.
-你懂我在说什么吗?
-完全懂
I know he's your best friend
but you do live with him.
我知道他是你的好朋友
但你跟他同住一室
I know...
我知道...
It's not that I don't like Ed.
Ed, it's not that I don't like you.
并非我不喜欢艾德
艾德,并非我不喜欢你
It's all right.
没关系
- It'd just be nice if we could...
- Fuck.
-只是如果我们能多花点时间相处...
-干
-..spend a bit more time together.
- Bollocks.
-会比较好
-混帐
- Just the two of us.
- Cock it.
-就我们两人
-妈的
With Ed here, it's no wonder
I always bring my flatmates out
有艾德跟着,难怪我老是
带我室友一块出来
and that only exacerbates things.
那只会使事情更加恶化
- What do you mean?
- You guys hardly get on, do you?
-什么意思?
-你们日子不太好过,是吧?
No, what does "exacerbate" mean?
不,“恶化”是什么意思?
It means to make things worse.
表示令事情越变越糟
Right, right.
对,对
Well, I mean, it's not that
I don't like David and Di, you know.
我意思是说,并非我不喜欢大卫和小黛
- Guys, it's not that I don't like you.
- It's all right.
-两位,并非我不喜欢你们
-没关系
And I do want to spend time with you.
我真的很希望多陪陪你
It's just Ed doesn't have too many friends.
只是艾德朋友不太多
Can I get any of you cunts a drink?
你们谁想喝一杯吗?
Anybody?
有人要吗?
No, thank you.
不用了,谢谢
I know...
我知道...
friends are important to Shaun
肖恩很重朋友
but you must set some
quality time aside for yourselves.
但你必须拨点时间给你们两人
Daffs is always taking me
to see these listed buildings
大卫总是带我去看些著名建筑物
and I'm always dragging him to the theatre.
我总是拖着他上戏院去
- I'm not so hot on theatre.
- How about a meal?
-我不太喜欢上戏院
-那去吃顿饭怎样?
- It's your anniversary soon.
- It was last week.
-你们周年纪念日快到了
-是在上礼拜
- Did you do anything special?
- We came here.
-你们有做什么特别的事吗?
-我们来了这里
Shaun. Hog lumps.
肖恩,猪肉豆干
Shaun, what I'm trying to say is
I need something more,
肖恩,我想说的是我需要更多的东西
more than spending every night
in the Winchester.
远远超过每晚待在温彻斯特
I want to do more interesting stuff.
我想做些更有趣的事
I want you to want to want to do it.
我要你希望想要去做
Listen to me.
I'm beginning to sound like your mum.
听听我,我开始像你妈一样唠叨了
- Not that I'd know.
- You haven't met his mum?
-我是不认识她啦
-你还没见过他妈?
- Not yet.
- Don't you get along with your mum?
-还没
-你跟你妈处不好吗?
- It's not her...
- Are you ashamed by your mum, Shaun?
-不是她的...
-你以你妈为耻吗,肖恩?
- No, I love my mum.
- I love his mum.
-不是,我爱我妈
-我爱他妈
- * She's like butter *
- Ed!
-“她像奶油一般”
-艾德!
- Shaun!
- Liz.
-肖恩!
-丽兹
I understand what
you're trying to say and I agree.
我明白你想说什么,我同意
We should get out there.
We'll start tomorrow.
我们应该离开,明天开始吧
I'll book a restaurant.
The place that does all the fish.
我会订一间餐厅,海鲜餐馆
Just the two of us.
就我们两人
Things will change. I promise.
情况会改变的,我保证
Really, Shaun?
真的吗,肖恩?
Time, gentlemen.
打烊了,各位
- * This town is coming like a ghost town *
- Shaun?
-"这座城镇逐渐像座鬼城"
-肖恩?
'Player two has entered the game.'
玩家二已进入游戏
Haven't you got work?
你不去上班吗?
'Player two has left the game.'
玩家二已离开游戏
The front door was open again last night.
昨晚前门又没关了
- I'm not saying it was you.
- I know, man.
-我没说是你
-我知道
- I'm saying it was Ed.
- Right.
-我说的是艾德
-对
I can't live like this.
我不能这样生活下去
Look at the state of it.
We're not students any more.
看看现在样子,我们不再是学生了
- Pete...
- He brings no money into the house.
-彼得...
-他一毛钱也没拿进这房子
- He brings a bit.
- What? Dealing drugs?
-他有拿一些回来
-什么? 卖毒品的钱吗?
He sells a bit of weed now and again.
You've sold puff.
他偶尔卖一些大麻,你也卖过大麻
Yeah, once. At college. To you.
对,就一次,在大学时,卖给了你
I've known him since primary school.
I like having him around, he's a laugh.
我从小学就认识他了
我喜欢他在一块,他是个开心果
Because he can
impersonate an orang-utan?
因为他会模仿红毛猩猩吗?
- Fuck-a-doodle-doo.
- Leave him alone.
-干他奶奶的
-放过他吧
I admit, he can be pretty funny on occasion.
我承认,有好几次他是相当搞笑
Like that time we stayed up all night drinking
apple schnapps and playing Tekken 2.
就像那次我们通宵没睡
喝苹果酒、玩《铁拳二代》电玩游戏
- When was that?
- Five years ago.
-什么时候的事?
-五年前
When's he going home?
他何时要回家?
Hey, man, listen... Top left.
嘿,听着...左上角
- Uh-huh.
- I was gonna say... Reload.
我要说... 上膛
- I'm on it.
- Erm, since... Nice shot!
-上了
-自从... 射的真准!
Thanks.
谢谢
Two seconds.
等我两秒
- All right, Noodle?
- 'Got anything?'
-好了,面条?
-有货吗?
- No, man.
- 'Eball says you was holding.'
-没有
-伊博说你有
- I ain't got nothing.
- 'Nothing at all?'
-我通通没了
-一点都没有?
I've only got an 'enry meself.
All right, laters.
我自己只剩下一点精力了
好了,晚点再说吧
- Listen...
- Ed...
-听着...
-艾德...
since you're not working at the moment
could you please clean up a bit?
既然你目前没工作
可不可以请你整理一下房子?
And if you play the answer machine,
can you take down everyone's messages?
如果你播放答录机的话
可以抄下每通留言吗?
- Yep.
- It's not that taxing, is it?
-好
-不是很粗重的活吧?
Writing something
on a scrap of paper?
在纸上写点字
- Nope.
- Right.
-不是
-好
Dom, hi...
(我是浑球)
唐,嗨...
Come on, it was pretty funny.
别这样,很好玩的
- Will you do what he said?
- I ain't doing nothing for him.
-你会照他说的去做吗?
-我不会为他做任何事
Do it for me, then.
那为我做吧
I'm sorry, Shaun.
对不起,肖恩
- It's all right.
- No, no.
-没关系
-不,不
I'm sorry, Shaun.
对不起,肖恩
Oh!
哦!
Oh, my God, that's rotten.
老天,真臭
- I'll stop doing 'em when you stop laughing.
- I am not laughing.
-你不笑我就不会再放屁了
-我没在笑
- Get that.
- You get it.
-接电话
-你去接
'Shaun, it's me.
I'm gonna be a bit tied up today
肖恩,是我,我今天会有点走不开
'so can you book the table
for eight rather than seven?
你能把订位从七点改成八点吗?
'I'll try you at work. Bye, bye.'
我上班时再打给你,拜拜
Hey! You're dead.
嘿! 你死定了
- Spare some change, please, mister?
- Yeah.
-麻烦赏点零钱吧,先生?
-好的
Watch out. Are you blind?
小心,你瞎了眼吗?
'The American
deep space probe Omega 6
美方太空探测船奥米茄六号...
'unexpectedly re-entered
Earth's atmosphere over England
意外地掉落英国上空大气层...
'and broke apart over...'
支离破碎的残骸遍及...
Nelson?
尼尔森?
Hello, my friend. No beer today?
你好,朋友,今天不买啤酒?
No, it's a bit early for me.
不,现在喝酒有点过早
Gather round, everyone.
Gather round, please.
大家集合,请集合一下
Gather round.
集合
As well as Mr Sloman being off today
今天不但所罗门先生没来上班
I'm afraid Ash is feeling
a little bit under the weather,
恐怕艾许也觉得身体有点不适
so I will be taking charge as the...
所以将由我负责,因为...
- Oldest.
- Senior staff member.
-是最老的
-是资深员工
So if we can all pull together...
所以只要我们同心协力...
- Hello? Hello, mate.
- Noel?
-喂? 你好呀,伙伴
-诺尔?
I was totally munted last night.
我昨晚完全气疯了
Yeah, I spoke to him. He's only got Henry.
对,我跟他讲了,他只找了亨利
All right, mate. Laters.
好了,伙伴,晚点再聊
- Continue.
- Thank you.
-继续说吧
-谢谢
Erm, as Mr Sloman always says,
there's no I in team but there is an I in pie.
就像所罗门先生常说的 团队(TEAM)中没有我(I)这个字
不过派(PIE)则有个我(I)
In... There's an I in meat pie.
在...在鲜肉派(MEAT PIE))有个我(I)字
The anagram of meat is team...
I don't know what he's talking about.
肉(MEAT)的拼字重组就是团队(TEAM)...
我不懂他的用意何在
Phones off. It's not a social gathering.
不准讲电话,又不是社交聚会
- All right, keep your hair on, grandad.
- Hey! I'm 29 for Christ's sakes.
-好了,你头都快秃了,老爷爷
-嘿! 拜我才29岁耶
- How old are you? 20? 21?
- 17.
-你多大年纪? 20? 21?
-17
Hey, well...
嘿,嗯...
I know you don't wanna be here forever.
I got things I wanna do with my life.
我知道你不想永远待在这儿
我这生也有很多事情想做
When?
什么时候?
You got red on you.
你衣服沾上红色了
Hello, mate.
你好呀,伙伴
This one comes with
a basic digital package.
这一台配备基本数位综合频道
You've got your lifestyle channels there,
a bit of Trisha.
有生活休闲频道,一些音乐频道
Er, you've got entertainment.
I don't know what that is.
有娱乐台,我不清楚那台是什么
News. All the basic, er...news...
新闻,所有基本频道...新闻...
- channels.
- 'bizarre events...'
-频道
-怪异事件...
'Coming after me...'
一直在追我...
- Shaun.
- I'm with customers.
-肖恩
-我有顾客
It's your dad.
是你爸
He's not my dad,
他不是我爸
he's my stepdad.
是我继父
Philip.
菲利普
Shaun.
肖恩
You haven't forgotten about tomorrow?
你没忘记明天的事吧?
- No.
- Your bimonthly visit.
-没有
-两个月一次的拜访
No, I haven't forgotten.
没有,我没忘
You could bring the flowers
you forgot on Mother's Day.
你可以补送母亲节忘了送的花
I was gonna.
我会的
And not a cheap posy
from a garage forecourt.
别送车库前院摘的廉价花朵
I wasn't gonna.
不会的
Well, we look forward to
seeing you tomorrow.
我们很期待明天见到你
OK.
好的
You've got red on you.
你衣服沾上红色了
- I thought it wasn't a social gathering?
- What?
-你不是说这不是社交聚会吗?
-什么?
How comes you're allowed to
speak to your dad?
为何你可以跟你爸聊天?
A, he's not my dad, OK? He's my stepdad.
A、他不是我爸,好吗? 他是我继父
And B, it was an emergency.
B、是紧急事件
What, like buying your mum some flowers?
怎么,比如买花给你妈吗?
Noel, I do not find it difficult
to keep my work and my social life separate.
诺尔,我不觉得把我的工作
和社交生活划分开来是很难的事
Shaun, it's Liz for you.
肖恩,丽兹找你
- Hello.
- 'Hello, it's me.'
-喂
-哈,是我
- Hello.
- 'Did you get my message?'
-哈
-你收到我的留言了吗?
- Yep.
- 'So it's all OK, then?'
-是
-那一切妥当了吧?
- Yep.
- 'Eight at the place with all the fish?
-是
-八点海鲜餐馆见了
'Cool, that's great. Just ring me later.'
酷,好极了,晚点打给我
- Goodbye, Liz.
- 'Bye. Bye, bye, bye.'
-再见,丽兹
-拜-拜-拜-拜
Liz from Head Office.
It's nothing to panic about.
总公司的丽兹打来的
没什么好紧张的
Sir? Sir?
先生? 先生?
Sorry. Erm, they're for my mum.
抱歉,是要送我妈的
Mum. "To a wonderful Mum"
or "Supermum"?
那要“致了不起的妈”
还是“超级老妈”卡片呢?
- Er...the first one.
- Right.
-第一个吧
-好
'.. London seems
to have gone completely bonkers...'
..伦敦似乎陷入一片完全疯狂中...
- Oh, my God! Shaun!
- Yvonne.
-老天! 肖恩!
-冯妮
Oooh! How are you doing?
哦! 你好吗?
- Surviving.
- Are you living round here?
-还活着
-你还住这附近吗?
- Yeah, are you?
- Yeah, I just bought a place.
-是的,你呢?
-是的,我刚买下一栋房子
- Bought?
- I know, bit grown-up, eh?
-买?
-我知道,有点年纪了
- Are you still with...?
- Liz.
-你还跟那个...?
-丽兹
That's great. Glad somebody made it.
How long's that been now?
太好了,很高兴有人成功
你们在一起多久了?
- Er, it's three years ago last week.
- Did you do anything special?
-上礼拜刚满三年
-你有做什么特别的事吗?
- We're going out for a meal tonight.
- Anywhere nice?
-我们今晚要出外用餐
-找到好地方了吗?
Yeah...
是的...
Come on!
快点!
- Are you gonna thank me, then?
- For what?
-你要感谢我吗?
-感谢什么?
Tidying up.
收拾整齐了
- It doesn't look tidy.
- I had a few beers when I finished.
-看起来一点也不整齐
-我收拾完时喝了几瓶啤酒
'Hello, Fulci's. Can you hold, please?'
你好,福气餐厅,请稍候片刻
- Do you want your messages?
- What?
-你要听你的留言吗?
-什么?
Your mum rang about tomorrow night.
你妈打电话来说明晚的事
Liz rang about the two of you
eating out tonight.
丽兹打电话说你们俩今晚外出用餐的事
Then your mum rang back to see
if I wanted to eat her out tonight.
然后你妈又打来问说
我今晚是否想跟她出去吃饭
- 'Hello, Fulci's.'
- Hi, I know it's short notice
-你好,福气餐厅
-嗨,我知道是临时通知
but could you possibly do me
a table for two for tonight at about eight?
但可否替我预订一个
今晚八点两人座位的桌子?
'Sorry, we just gave away the last table.'
抱歉,最后一桌刚刚被订走了
Wasn't true about your mum.
你妈来电的事是骗你的
Where are we gonna go?
我们怎么办? 要去哪间吃呢?
- The Winchester.
- Don't be stupid! They don't do food.
-温彻斯特
-别傻了! 那间根本不会煮菜
- There's a Breville out back.
- Ed, this is serious!
-后面有一间布列维尔
-艾德,这事很重要!
Hello.
喂
- 'Hello, it's me.'
- Hello.
-哈,是我
-哈
'What's the plan, then?'
那计划怎样啦?
Erm, there's been a bit of a...
a mix-up with the table, babe.
宝贝,订桌位的事有点...难搞
- 'What do you mean?'
- They're full up.
-什么意思?
-位子满了
'But...I thought you said it was all OK?'
但...我以为你说一切没问题的?
Yeah.
没错
'You didn't book it, did you, Shaun?'
你没订位是吧,肖恩?
- No.
- 'So...what is the plan, then?'
-没有
-那么...计划怎么办?
The Winchester?
温彻斯特?
- 'Hello?'
- Dianne, can you let me in?
-喂?
-黛安,可以让我进去吗?
- 'I'm not sure, Shaun.'
- Oh, come on.
-我不太确定,肖恩
-哦,别这样嘛
'Lizzie doesn't want to see you.'
小丽不想见你,肖恩,走吧
- Just open the door!
- 'She doesn't want to see you.'
-开门就是了!
-她不想见你,肖恩
Do you want me to climb up the wall,
come through the window? Because I will.
你要我怎样?
要我爬墙从窗户进去吗? 因为我会的
'You're not coming in.'
你进不来的
- OK, see you in a minute.
- 'Don't...'
-好吧,待会见了
-别...
'Hi, it's me again.'
嗨,又是我
Can we just talk about this? Let's go out.
可以谈一下吗? 我们出去吧
- To the Winchester?
- Do you want to?
-去温彻斯特吗?
-你想去那间吗?
- No, I don't fucking want to!
- OK.
-不,我他妈的才不想!
-好的
It's not the only place in the world.
全世界又不是只剩那间了
We'll go to the Shepherd's,
they do Thai in there.
我们去牧羊人餐厅吃泰国菜
- I'm going out with David and Di.
- Let's go together.
-我要跟大卫和小黛一块出去
-我们一起去吧
You hang out with my friends?
"A failed actress and a twat"?
你要约我朋友去吗?
“一个过气女星和一个智障”?
That's harsh.
I did not call Dianne a failed actress.
那么说太难听了
我没说过黛安是过气女星
Let's just go somewhere and have a laugh.
Things'll be fine, I promise.
我们找个地方开怀一下
没问题的,我保证
You promised you'd stop smoking.
你保证你会戒菸
You promised you'd try drinking
red wine instead of beer!
你保证会尝试喝红酒而不是啤酒!
- You promised we'd go on holiday.
- We went to Greece!
-你保证我们会去渡假
-我们去了希腊呀!
- We met in Greece.
- At a rave.
-我们在希腊认识的
-大吵相识的
It's not the same.
You promised things would change.
这不一样,你保证事情会改变的
- You promised us free cable.
- I'm working on that.
-你保证我们会有免费有线电视看
-我正在处理
I can give up smoking whenever I want.
See, don't need them.
菸我随时想戒就能戒
瞧,不需要了
W-What was the next one?
接下来说的是什么?
It's not enough, Shaun.
不够的,肖恩
'We appear to have
a breakdown in communication there.
通讯似乎有点不良...
'lf you or someone you know may...'
如果你或你认识的人可能...
I'd say your nine lives were up, Shaun.
看来你的九条命已经完蛋了,肖恩
Get fucked, four-eyes!
滚开,四眼田鸡!
You go out with her, you love her so much.
你跟他出去,你很爱她吗?
What do you mean by that?
那句话什么意思?
'..the devastation really is extensive.
It's a total mess.'
..惨况不断扩大中,陷入一阵混乱
I don't know what he meant by that.
我不懂他那句话的意思
Got you these.
这些花送你
- "To a wonderful mum"?
- Oooh!
-“致了不起的妈”?
-哦!
Yeah, that's because...
没错,那是因为...
I thought it would be funny
because of what you said last night
我想这样可能会很好玩
因为你昨晚说到...
about you don't want to be
my mum and that.
关于你不希望变成我老妈那样唠叨的事
It's just a little joke,
just sort of spur of the moment.
只是开个小小玩笑,增加一点生活情趣
- They're for your mum, aren't they?
- Yeah.
-花是要送给你妈的,对吧?
-对
Smooth.
没诚意
If I don't do something, I'll end up in that pub
我再不想点办法,我这后半辈子...
for the rest of my life
like those other sad old fuckers
就会像其他那些可悲的老混蛋
终日窝在酒吧里头...
wondering what the hell happened.
不断纳闷着到底怎么回事
What do you mean do something?
你是说想点办法吗?
(Winchester Tavern)
(温彻斯特酒馆)
Fuck her. You got your pint.
去她的! 你有酒
You got your pig snacks.
What more do you want?
有猪肉干,你还想要什么?
Oh. You want your favourite monkey?
哦,你想要你最喜欢的猴子吗?
Shall I do Clyde?
要我扮作克莱德吗?
See, I knew you'd get over her.
瞧,我知道你忘得了她的
* If you leave me now... *
"如果你现在离开我..."
Who the hell put this on?
到底是谁放这首歌的?
It's on random.
是随机播放的
For fuck's sake. John, yes please, mate.
他妈的! 约翰,麻烦一下
You know what we should do tomorrow?
Keep drinking.
你知道我们明天该怎样吗?
继续喝酒
A Bloody Mary first thing,
先喝一杯血腥玛丽
a bite at the King's Head,
couple at The Little Princess,
下盘棋,到“小公主”打个泡
stagger back here and bang...
back at the bar for shots.
回到这里...回到酒吧喝几杯
How's that for a slice of fried gold?
那样子你觉得如何?
- No.
- Come on, man.
-不
-别这样,老兄
Talk to me.
跟我说说
She said if she stayed with me
she'd end up in here for the rest of her life
她说如果再跟着我下去
到头来她后半辈子会窝在这里
Iike these sad old fuckers
wondering what the hell happened.
像这些可悲的老混蛋
不断纳闷着怎么回事
That is harsh.
这话真难听
- These are rich, interesting characters.
- Like who?
-这些人又有钱又有趣
-比如说谁?
Snakehips. Always surrounded by women.
蛇王,总是被女人所包围
He's a bigamist.
他是个重婚者
Strangled his first wife
with a draught excluder.
用排气管废气令他第一任老婆窒息死亡
And invented the mobile disco.
还开狄斯可舞会庆祝呢
What about her, then?
那她怎样?
Ooh! Cockacidal maniac.
哦! 吹萧狂
She's an ex-porn star.
她之前是Ａ片女星
They say she starred in
the world's first interracial hardcore loop.
听说她演出全球第一部
集合各色人种的春宫片
Cafe Au Lait...
咖啡牛奶...
Pour Vous.
射出来了
Yeah. What about John, then?
对,那约翰怎样?
He's North London Mafia.
他是北伦敦黑手党党员
It's true, Big Al says so.
真的,大艾尔说的
Yeah, Big Al also says dogs can't look up.
对,大艾尔也说狗是色盲
Think about it. Handy with a blade.
Gruff demeanour.
你想想看,刀法纯熟、面无表情
Bernie, the trophy wife.
柏妮是他赏来的老婆
He's connected.
Why is there a rifle above the bar?
他一定有关连,不然酒吧上方
为何摆着一把莱福枪?
- The pub's called the Winchester.
- Exactly.
-这间酒吧叫作温彻斯特呀
-一点儿也没错
See, you don't need Liz to have a good time.
瞧吧,你不需要丽兹也能开心过日子
- Don't, man.
- No.
-哦,少来
-不
Oi, look at me.
看着我
Can I just say one thing? I'm not gonna
say there's plenty more fish in the sea,
我能说一件事吗?
我不会说“天涯何处无芳草”
I'm not gonna say if you love her let her go
我不会说“爱她就要让她走”
and I'm not gonna bombard you with cliches
but what I will say is this...
我也不会用些陈腔滥调安慰你
但我会这么说...
it's not the end of the world.
这又不是世界末日
Sorry, we're closed.
抱歉,我们打烊了
Pisshead.
猪头
* Ooh, white lines
"哦,白线"
* Visions, dreams of passion
"幻影、热情梦想"
* Going through my mind
"掠过我心头"
* And all the while I think of you...
"每当我一想起你..."
Oh?
哦?
What's the matter, love,
haven't you had your tea?
怎么了,亲爱的,还没喝茶吗?
* Something of a phenomenon
telling my body to come along
"某种现象驱使我身体前进"
* Cos white lines
"因为白线"
* Blow away...
- Shh!
-"吹走了..."
-嘘!
Blow!
砰!
* Ah, get higher, baby
"啊,高兴点,宝贝"
* Ah, get higher, baby, ah, get higher, girl
"啊,高兴点,宝贝! 啊,高兴点,小妞!"
* Ah... *
"啊..."
What? He should say base.
怎么? 他应该说“站在原地”
Or freeze.
或者“不准动”
What a tit.
真是笨蛋
* You wanna dance? *
"你想跳舞吗?"
Don't scratch it! Wait...
别刮坏了! 等等...
- That was the second album I ever bought!
- It's four in the fucking morning!
-那是我买过的第二张唱片!
-他妈的现在是凌晨四点呀!
- It's Saturday!
- No, it's not.
-星期六呀!
-不,不是
It's fucking Sunday
and I've got to go to fucking work
是该死的星期天,在过他妈的四小时
in four fucking hours
because every other fucker is fucking ill!
我还得他妈的上班
因为其他混蛋都他妈的生病了!
Now can you see why I'm so fucking angry?
现在明白为何我他妈的这样生气吗?
- Fuck, yeah!
- Hey! Pete, look,
-没错,真干!
-嘿! 彼得,听着
I'm sorry, we had a couple of drinks,
we split up with Liz tonight.
很抱歉,我们喝了几杯酒
今晚我跟丽兹分手了
Just keep it down, yeah?
小声点,好吗?
Prick.
浑球
What was that?
你说什么?
Nothing.
没什么
- Stop it, we're friends!
- He's not my friend. He's a fucking idiot.
-住手,我们是朋友呀!
-他才不是我朋友,他是该死的白痴
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It means why don't you fuck off!
-那是什么意思?
-意思是你为何不滚蛋!
You wanna live like an animal,
live in the shed, you thick fuck!
你想像个畜生过活
住在猪圈里,你这超级混蛋!
- Leave him alone!
- Stop defending him.
-放过他吧!
-别老护着他,肖恩
All he ever does is hold you back.
他只会拖累你
Or is it easier having someone around
who's more of a loser than you?
还是说找个比你窝囊的人在身边
会让你比较好过?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- You know what I mean.
-那是什么意思?
-你懂我的意思
I assume it was Liz who did the dumping?
我认为是丽兹甩了你
Sort your fucking life out, mate.
整理一下你该死的生活吧,伙伴
What's up with your hand, man?
你的手怎么了?
- I got mugged on the way home from work.
- By who?
-我下班回家时在路上被人攻击
-被谁?
- Some crackheads. One of them bit me.
- Why?
-几个疯子,其中一个咬了我
-为何咬你?
I don't know, I didn't stop to ask them!
我不知道,我又没停车叫他们咬我!
I've got a splitting headache
and your stupid hip hop isn't helping.
我头痛的要命
你那愚蠢的嘻哈乐害得我更疼
And the front door is open. Again!
前门又没关了!
It's not hip hop, it's electro. Prick.
那不是嘻哈乐,是电子乐,浑球
Next time I see him, he's dead.
下回再让我看到他,他就死定了
'Shaun, it's me.
I'm gonna be a bit tied up today
肖恩,是我,我今天会有点走不开
'so can you book the table
for eight rather than seven?
你能把订位从七点改成八点吗?
'I'll try you at work. Bye, bye.'
我上班时再打给你,拜拜
'Hello, pickle. It's me, Mum.
哈,小捣蛋,是妈
'Dad mentioned you might be visiting
tomorrow which would be lovely.
你爸跟我提说你可能明天会来看我们
那真是太好了
'Will you be bringing
Elizabeth with you this time?
你这次会带伊莉莎白一块来吗?
'Only we can't wait to meet her finally
我们迫不急待终于能见到她了
'and also I was wondering
if she wanted anything special for lunch?
我也在想说不知道她午餐喜欢吃什么?
'Cos these days a lot of people
don't eat meat.'
因为这几天很多人不吃肉
Do you want anything from the shop?
要我帮你从店里带点什么吗?
Cornetto.
甜筒
Nelson, have you got any papers?
尼尔森,你有纸吗?
Nelson? I haven't even...
尼尔森? 我甚至没有...
I owe you about 15p.
我欠你15块左右
Oh dear.
老天
Sorry, I haven't got any change.
抱歉,我没零钱了
I didn't even have enough
at the fucking shop. Oh dear.
我甚至去店里买东西都不够钱了
'..no official comment but religious groups
are calling it Judgement Day. There's...'
..尚未有官方说明
不过宗教团体宣称是审判日,有...
*..panic on the streets of London... *
"..伦敦大街一片恐慌..."
- '..number of reports of...'
- '..serious attacks on...'
-..大量的报导说...
-..严重的攻击...
- '..people who are being...'
- '..eaten alive.'
-..人类被...
-..生吃活剥
'Witness reports are sketchy.
One unifying detail seems to be
目击者说词简略,归纳出结果似乎...
'that the attackers appear to be...'
攻击者显然是...
'..the sensational chart-topping...'
..轰动一时的热门焦点...
'..or ideological connection between
those committing the atrocities...'
..或是那些犯下暴行者之间
有着意识形态上的连结...
There's a girl in the garden.
花园里有个女孩子
- '..emergency services...'
- What?
-..紧急救难中心...
-什么?
In the garden, there is a girl.
花园里有个女孩子
'..the armed forces will be called in
to provide backup and assistance.
..召集了武装部队前来提供支援和协助
'Scientists are still trying to establish
the nature of the phenomenon
科学家们还在尝试研究这种自然现象
'and are unsure as to the...'
尚未得出确定结果...
Excuse me.
抱歉
Hello.
哈
- What are you doing?
- Oi!
你在干嘛呀?
Oh, my God.
哦,老天
She's so drunk.
她醉晕头了
How much have you had, love?
你喝了多少呀,亲爱的?
- Oh! I think she likes you.
- Shut up.
-哦! 我想她喜欢你
-闭嘴
- She wants a cuddle!
- I've just come out of a relationship.
-她想要抱抱!
-我刚刚失恋
- Ed, do something!
- Wait there.
-艾德,想想办法!
-等一下
- Ed!
- Two seconds.
-艾德!
-多等我一下
I'm really flattered and everything but...
我真的受宠若惊,只不过...
And, hold it there.
别动
Ed! Just get her off me.
艾德! 把她拉开
Jesus!
老天!
- What's up with her eyes?
- Now, seriously...
-她的眼睛怎么回事?
-现在我郑重告诉你...
Mary, I'm warning you,
I'll have to get physical, I mean it!
玛丽,我警告你,
我会上了你的,我说真的!
This is it... Look, just fuck off!
到此为止... 听着,滚开!
- I think we should go back inside.
- OK.
-我想我们该回屋内去
-好的
- Shaun, what's going on?
- Shit, it's engaged.
-肖恩,怎么回事?
-可恶,忙线中
- How about an ambulance?
- It's engaged, Ed.
-叫辆救护车如何?
-忙线中啊,艾德
- Fire engine?
- It's one number and it's busy!
-消防队呢?
-就同一个号码而且忙线中啊!
- And what do you want a fire engine for?
- Anything with flashing lights.
-再说找消防队要干嘛?
-车子有亮闪光灯的都好
Are they still out there?
他们还在外头吗?
Yeah. What do you think we should do?
是的,你想我们该怎么办?
Have a sit-down?
坐下来休息?
'There are reports of chaos
on the motorways
高速公路交通数度混乱...
'as thousands of people
attempt to flee the cities.
数千名民众打算飞快逃离都市
'The M1, the M3, M4, M6...'
M1线、M3线、M4线、M6线...
- Do you think this is the same thing?
- '..are all at a standstill.
-你认为是同一档子的事吗?
-..交通全都动弹不得
'The Home Office is urging people to stay
in their homes and await further instruction.'
内务部催促民众待在自己家中
等候进一步的指示
'Ensure all residences are secure
为了确保所有居民安全
'with all doors and windows
firmly locked and barricaded. Police...'
所有门窗要确实锁好堵住,警方...
- For God's sake! He's got an arm off!
- Get him!
-我的妈呀! 他一只手没了!
-砸他!
'More reports just in confirm that in all cases
the attackers seem slow and shambolic...'
刚刚证实了更多则报导
所有的攻击者行动迟缓、怪异...
I'm gonna shut the front door.
我去把前门关好
'..regarding the best way
to neutralise the attackers.
..至于对付攻击者的最佳办法...
'ln the meantime, contact with
these assailants is highly inadvisable.'
同时,接触这些攻击者是极为不智的作法
- Did you see his head go?
- 'lf you're confronted...'
-你看到他头的样子吗?
-如果你们遭遇到...
- We should get out there.
- No, we should stay inside.
-我们该离开这里
-不,我们应该留在屋内
- We can take 'em.
- The man said to stay indoors.
-我们对付得了他们
-这人说要留在屋内
- Fuck the man.
- In here, we're safe.
-叫这人去死啦
-他们在屋外,我们留在屋内才安全
'..the attackers can be stopped by removing
the head or destroying the brain.
..藉由砍掉头部或摧毁脑部
可以阻止攻击者的行动
'I'll repeat that, by removing the head
or destroying the brain.'
重覆一遍,砍掉头部或摧毁脑部
Hey!
嘿!
Aim for the head.
瞄准头部
- Now what?
- Get more stuff.
-现在怎么办?
-拿更多东西来吧
- What's in the shed?
- Dunno, it's locked.
-仓库里有什么?
-不知道,锁住了
- Why is it locked?
- It's always been locked.
-干嘛锁起来?
-一直以来就是锁住的
No! That's the second album I ever bought!
不! 那是我买过的第二张唱片!
Some of these are limited...
Ah! What was that?
有些是限量发行的...
啊! 那张是什么?
- Blue Monday.
- That was an original pressing.
-《忧郁星期一》
-那张是最初版呀
For fuck's sake.
好吧
- Erm...Purple Rain?
- No.
-《紫雨》呢?
-不行
- Sign O' The Times?
- Definitely not.
-《时代的象征》呢?
-绝对不行
- The Batman soundtrack?
- Throw it.
-《蝙蝠侠》原声带?
-丢吧
- Dire Straits?
- Throw it.
-《险峻海峡乐团》?
-丢吧
- Er... Ooh, Stone Roses?
- No.
-哦,《石玫瑰乐团》?
-不行
- Second Coming?
- I like it.
-《再次出击》?
-我喜欢那张
Ah! Sade?
《莎黛》?
- That's Liz's.
- She dumped you.
-那张是丽兹的
-她甩掉你了
- I'm going to the shed.
- You said it was locked.
-我去仓库
-你说锁住了呀
- Which one do you want? Girl or bloke?
- Er...the first one.
-你想对付哪一个? 男的女的?
-第一个吧
'People receiving bites
have experienced headaches and nausea
被咬到的人会产生头痛、反胃...
'and developed symptoms...'
以及攻击性的症状...
You've got red on you.
你衣服沾到红色了
'lf you know someone who has been bitten
如果你知道谁被咬了
'it is absolutely essential
that you isolate them immediately.
当务之急便是立刻将他们隔离起来
'The public are being strongly advised
not to approach anyone...'
强烈呼吁大众千万别去接近任何人...
Pete?
彼得?
- Why don't we just go up?
- Don't go up there!
-我们何不直接上楼?
-别上楼!
- Why not?
- Because A, he might be one of them
-为何不要?
-因为: A、他可能跟他们一样
and B, he might still be annoyed.
B、他可能还在生气
Pete?
彼得?
Maybe he went into work.
也许他去上班了
How come he didn't drive?
His keys are still here.
他怎么没开车?
他的车钥匙还在这里
Maybe he got a lift.
He said he wasn't feeling well. Pete?
也许有人载他
他说他身体不舒服,彼得?
Oi, prick!
浑球!
He's not in.
他不在
- You got a fag?
- No, I've given up.
-你有菸吗?
-没有,我戒了
- Since when?
- Since...
-啥时戒的?
-自从...
Come on, babe. Oh, she's engaged.
快点,宝贝! 哦,她电话不通
- That was quick.
- Ed, this is serious.
-速度还真快
-艾德,事态严重
Liz!
丽兹!
- 'Shaun.'
- Mum! I was gonna call you. Are you OK?
-肖恩
-妈! 我正要打给你,你没事吧?
- 'Yes.'
- Are you sure?
-是的
-你确定?
'Some men tried to get into the house.'
有些人想进到屋子里来
- Are they still there?
- 'I'm not sure. We shut the curtains.'
-他们还在那里吗?
-不太清楚,窗帘拉上了
- Did you try the police?
- 'Well, I thought about it.'
-你有报警吗?
-嗯,是有想过
- Are you OK? Did they hurt you?
- 'No, I'm fine.'
-你还好吗? 他们有没有伤害你?
-没有,我很好
- Mum?
- 'Well...they were a bit bitey.'
-妈?
-嗯...他们被咬伤了
- Mum, have you been bitten?
- 'No, but Philip has.'
-妈,你被咬了吗?
-没有,不过菲利普被咬了
- Oh, OK.
- Has she been bitten?
-哦,好的
-她被咬了吗?
- No, Philip has.
- Oh, OK.
-没有,菲利普被咬了
-哦,好的
- Mum, what state is he in?
- 'He's fine. Bit under the weather.'
-妈,他现在情况怎样?
-他没事,身体有点不适
- I see.
- What's the deal?
-我明白了
-怎样?
We may have to kill my stepdad.
Mum, you're not safe there. I'm coming.
我们可能得去宰掉我继父
妈,你那儿不太安全,我这就过去
- 'I don't want to cause a fuss.'
- We're coming to get you, Barbara!
-我不想搞得大惊小怪
-我们去接你了,芭芭拉!
So, what's the plan?
计划如何?
Right.
好
'We take Pete's car, we drive over to Mum's,
我们开彼得的车去我妈家
'we go in, we take care of Philip.'
一进去就先解决掉菲利普
I'm so sorry, Philip.
抱歉了,菲利普
'Then we grab Mum, go over to Liz's place,
然后我们抓住妈,再去丽兹家
'hole up, have a cup of tea
窝在屋里,喝杯茶
'and wait for all this to blow over.'
然后静待一切风平浪静
- Why have we got to go to Liz's?
- Because we do.
-干嘛非要去丽兹家?
-因为非去不可
- She dumped you.
- I have to know if she's all right.
-她甩了你呀
-我必须知道她是否平安无事
- Why?
- Because I love her.
-为什么?
-因为我爱她
All right, gay.
好吧,玻璃
- I'm not staying there, though.
- Why not?
-我不要待在那里
-为何不要?
If we hole up,
I want to be somewhere familiar,
如果我们要窝在哪,我想在熟悉的地方
I wanna know where the exits are
and I wanna be allowed to smoke.
我要知道出口在哪,而且可以抽菸
OK...
好吧...
'Take Pete's car, go round Mum's,
开彼得的车到妈家
'go in, deal with Philip.'
进屋去,解决掉菲利普
Sorry, Philip.
抱歉了,菲利普
'Grab mum, go to Liz's,
pick her up, bring her back here,
抓住妈,到丽兹家
接她上车,带她回这里来
'have a cup of tea
and wait for all this to blow over.'
喝杯茶,静待一切风平浪静
Perfik.
完美
No, wait, we can't bring them back here.
不,等等,我们不能带她们回这里来
- Why not?
- It's not exactly safe, is it?
-为何不行?
-不太安全,是吧?
Yeah. Look at the state of it.
对,看看这里的样子
Where's safe? Where's familiar?
哪里既安全又熟悉呢?
Where can I smoke?
哪里我可以抽菸呢?
'Take car, go to Mum's, kill Phil.'
开车,去妈家,杀了菲利普
- Sorry.
- 'Grab Liz, go to the Winchester,
-抱歉了
-接了丽兹,去温彻斯特
'have a nice cold pint
and wait for all this to blow over.'
喝杯冰啤酒,静待一切风平浪静
How's that for a slice of fried gold?
那样子你觉得如何?
Yeah, boy!
好耶,小子!
'To recap, it is vital
that you stay in your homes.
重覆声明,务必留在自己家中
'Make no attempt to reach loved ones
千万别企图去找心爱的人
'and avoid all physical contact
with the assailants.'
避免与攻击者有任何的肢体接触
Do you believe everything you hear on TV?
你相信电视上说的一切吗?
Yeah, I can see it, it's just outside.
我看到了,就在外面
Any zombies out there?
外面有僵尸吗?
- Don't say that.
- What?
-别说那个
-什么?
- That.
- What?
-那个
-什么?
That. The Z word. Don't say it.
那个,“僵”开头那个字,别说出来
- Why not?
- Because it's ridiculous.
-为何不行?
-因为太荒唐了
All right. Are there any out there, though?
好吧,外面有吗?
Can't see any.
Maybe it's not as bad as all that.
没看见,也许情形并没那么糟糕
Oh! No, there they are.
哦! 不,看到他们了
- OK, let's do this, yeah?
- Yeah?
-好,进行吧,好吗?
-好吗?
Yeah! I got to do a wee first.
好! 我得先去小便一下
Ooh...can I drive?
哦...可以让我开车吗?
What?
什么?
I always wanted to drive Pete's car.
I might not get another chance.
我一直想开开看彼得的车
很可能再也没机会了
OK.
行
Ahh! Oh, God.
哦,老天
Sorry, Pete. Listen, we're gonna
borrow your car, OK?
抱歉,彼得!
听着,我们要借用一下你的车,好吗?
Erm, we'll bring it back.
我们会开回来还你的
And if you're feeling better later,
we're...we're going to the pub.
如果你待会觉得舒服点
我们...我们要去酒吧
You're more than welcome to, er...
欢迎你一块儿来...
join us.
加入我们
Pete'd be so pissed off
if he knew I was driving his car.
彼得如果知道我开他的车,肯定气炸了
I don't think so.
我想也是
Shaun, which button's central locking?
肖恩,中控锁是哪个按钮?
Oh, cock it!
哦,走吧!
Get lost!
滚开!
Drive.
开车
'The Church of England
has joined other extremist religious groups
英国教会已经加入宣称此事为...
'in proclaiming this
"a sign of a coming apocalypse".
“未来启示录的象征”
的极端主义者之宗教团体
'Downing Street is refusing
to be drawn into a religious debate.
唐宁街部份拒绝涉入宗教辩论
'The bodies of the recently deceased
are returning to life and attacking the living.'
最近死亡的尸体逐渐复活并攻击活人
Let's put something else on.
听点别的吧
What are you doing? Ed, look out!
你在干嘛呀? 艾德,小心!
I think we hit something.
我想我们撞到东西了
Or someone.
或者撞到人了
Ow!
喔!
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Come on, let's just go.
快点,我们走吧
Hello?
喂?
- He's gonna be dead either way.
- That's not the point.
-反正他迟早会死
-那不是重点
Oh, thank God for that.
哦,幸好是那个
Ah, hello.
哈
Who's a pretty boy then?
那辆漂亮车子是的的呀?
You didn't say Barbara had a Jag.
I've always wanted to drive a Jag.
你没说过芭芭拉有辆积架
我一直很想开开看积架
It's Philip's. He won't let anybody near it.
那是菲利普的车,他不会让任何人靠近的
I put a Mars Bar in it once
and he chased me with a bit of wood.
我曾经放了一条火星牌巧克力在车内
他就拿根木棍追着我跑
- Fuck, it's gorgeous.
- It seems pretty clear, we should go.
-干,真漂亮
-似乎满安全的,我们该走了
Why don't I stay here?
何不我留在车里?
What, what, what, what, what?
什么,什么...?
You know, just look after the car.
If there's any problems...
你知道的,看车呀
如果出了任何问题...
I'll honk three times.
我会鸣喇叭三声
OK.
好吧
Don't forget to kill Philip!
别忘了宰掉菲利普!
- Hello, pickle.
- Hi, Mum.
-哈,小捣蛋
-嗨,妈
You've got red on you.
你身上沾到红色了
Yeah. Mum, is everything OK?
Are you all right?
嗯,妈,一切没事吧?
你没事吧?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- Where's Philip?
-是的,我没事
-菲利普在哪?
- Dad's in the lounge.
- He's not my dad.
-你爸在休息室
-他不是我爸
Really!
真的!
Ed's outside,
we'll take you somewhere safe.
艾德人在外头,我们要带你去安全的地方
- What about the doctor?
- I don't think he's gonna come.
-医生呢?
-我想医生不会来了
- Philip won't want to leave the house.
- Philip isn't...
-菲利普不想离开这房子
-菲利普不是...
Put the kettle on and I'll deal with Philip.
你去烧开水,我去找菲利普
- OK.
- OK, then.
-好的
-那好吧
- You hungry?
- Not really.
-肚子饿吗?
-不太饿
- I'll make some sandwiches.
- OK.
-我弄点三明治
-好的
No fighting, you two.
你们两个别吵起来唷
'..you may ask where is our God?
..你或许问说上帝在哪?
'But throughout the land,
men and women of integrity
但是全国各地,完好无缺的男男女女们
'rise up to confront the unseen enemy.
挺身对抗这未知的敌人
'They will not be cowards,
他们将不再当个懦夫
'they will be courageous
in the face of danger.'
他们将勇敢面对危险
- I'm so sorry, Philip.
- Why?
-我很抱歉,菲利普
-为什么?
- What have you done now?
- Nothing.
-你干了什么事吗?
-没事
What have you got there? Flowers, I hope.
你手上拿着什么? 希望那是花
No, it's...cricket bat.
不,这是...板球棒
- Is that for the jumble, Shaun?
- No. Yes.
-那是不是要义卖的,肖恩?
-不...是的
Your toys are upstairs.
I was going to give them to the jumble.
你的玩具在楼上,我要拿去作义卖
- I took them all to the tip, Barbara.
- What?
-我通通丢到垃圾场了,芭芭拉
-什么?
- Shaun wants to take us somewhere.
- Don't be silly.
-肖恩想带我们去别的地方
-别傻了
Maybe you should stay here
and wait for the doctor.
也许我们该留在这儿等医生来
- You said he wasn't coming.
- You didn't call the doctor?
-你刚说医生不会来了
-你没叫医生,对吧?
- Just to be on the safe side.
- I'm fine. I ran it under a cold tap.
-只是为了安全起见
-我很好,我用冷水清洗过伤口了
We had our jabs when
we went to the lsle of Wight.
我们去威特岛时也受过伤
- But, Philip...
- It's overblown nonsense.
-菲利普,可是...
-真是荒诞到极点
- A lot of drug nuts running wild.
- But I should get Mum away.
-一堆吸毒疯子在撒野
-但我应该接妈离开
- I'm not going anywhere without Philip.
- Mum, look!
-菲利普不走,我哪儿也不去
-妈,听着!
How about that tea?
喝杯茶怎样?
Mum, how much do you love Philip?
妈,你爱菲利普有多深?
- Two sugars, is it?
- I haven't had sugar in my tea since 1982.
-加两颗糖吗?
-自从1982年起,我茶里就不加糖了
Oh, yes. Will you cut me some bread, love?
没错,帮我切点面包好吗?
Mum, look, how much do you love Philip?
妈,听着,你爱菲利普有多深?
Do we have to go through all that again?
我们非要再讨论一遍吗?
What would you say if I told you
that Philip's been quite unkind to me?
如果我跟你说菲利普对我一直不太好
你会怎么说?
You weren't easy to live with.
你那时不太容易相处
- He chased me with a bit of wood!
- You did call him a you-know-what.
-他曾拿根木棍追我呀!
-你叫他同性恋啊
- Did he tell you that? Motherfucker.
- Shaun!
-他那么跟你说吗? 王八蛋
-没错! 肖恩!
Sorry, Mother... Mum!
对不起,母亲... 妈!
Did you know that on several occasions...
he touched me?
你知道有好几次...他碰触我吗?
That wasn't true.
Made it up, shouldn't have, sorry.
那不是真的
我瞎编的,我不该那样,抱歉
- You don't understand...
- No, you don't understand.
-你不懂...
-不,你才不懂
Philip is my husband
and has been for 1 7 years
菲利普是我老公,我们结婚十七年了
and I would at least expect you
to respect my feelings.
希望你至少尊重一下我的感情
You must be more adult about these things.
你一定要更加成熟看待这些事
Yeah.
没错
Come on, Shaun.
There comes a time when...
拜,肖恩,也该是时候了...
you just...
你得...
gotta be a man.
当个男子汉
I'm telling you, it's a fuss over nothing.
我告诉你,根本是大惊小怪
Hello, Edward.
你好,艾德华
- Hi, Barbara.
- My, how you've grown.
-你好,芭芭拉
-哇,你长这么大了
You better believe it.
What happened? Why is he coming?
你最好相信吧
怎么搞的? 他怎会跟来?
- It wasn't as easy as all that.
- Are we following you?
-并不全都那么容易
-我们跟着你们走吗?
No, it's probably best if we...
Where's the car?
不,可能最好是我们...
车子呢?
Hmm...I pranged it.
撞烂了
You were parked.
你才停个车呀
Yeah.
对
I guess we'll have to take the Jag.
我猜我们得坐积架车了
- Philip?
- What?
-菲利普?
-什么事?
Look out!
小心!
Christ!
老天!
- Give me the car keys!
- You're not driving that car.
-车钥匙给我!
-你别想开那辆车
Give me the car keys!
Ed, get Mum in the car.
车钥匙给我!
艾德,叫妈上车
I'm on it.
没问题
Don't worry about me.
Worry about your mother.
别担心我,担心你妈吧
- Maybe I should drive.
- I've adjusted the seat now.
-也许该由我来开
-我座位调整好了呀
Just be careful!
只要小心点!
Can you please turn that noise down?
拜把那噪音关掉好吗?
Are you all right, dear?
Would you like another tissue?
你还好吧,亲爱的? 面纸还要吗?
I'd be fine if it weren't for that bloody racket.
要不是那该死的噪音,我就没事
- It is a bit loud.
- Sorry, Barbara.
-是有点吵
-抱歉,芭芭拉
You do realise this is
a 20 mile an hour zone?
你们晓得这里限速20哩吗?
Oh, yeah.
晓得
- Here.
- Mum, this won't take a second, all right?
-到了
-妈,一下子就好,行吗?
- Have you still got the child locks on?
- Safety first, Shaun.
-你还装了幼童安全锁?
-安全第一,肖恩
You can't...
你不能...
Hey, man, watch the leather.
嘿,小心皮椅
Keep moving. If there's any problems...
继续开,如果有麻烦的话...
I'll do the honks.
我会按喇叭的
'Hello?'
喂?
Hello?
- Guys, can you let me in?
- What are you doing?
-大伙,能让我进去吗?
-你在干嘛呀?
I've come to get you.
我来接你的
- What are you doing?
- I've come to take you somewhere safe.
-肖恩,你做什么?
-我来带你去安全的地方
- We were safe!
- You don't know that.
-我们在这儿安全的很!
-你并不清楚
There was two of them out there.
How many are there now?
之前外面才两个,现在有几个了?
- Lots.
- Lots!
-一大堆
-一大堆!
It only takes one of them
to know you're in here.
相信我,只要他们其中一个
知道你们在这里面就完了
I tried calling but I couldn't get through.
I had to come up with a plan.
我一直打电话都打不通
我只好拟定一个计划
- Oh, you made a plan?
- We have to get out of here.
-哦,你定了一个计划?
-我们必须离开这里
If we don't, they'll tear us to pieces.
如果不离开,他们会把我们分尸的
And that will exacerbate things for all of us.
那会使我们事情恶化的
- Shaun...
- This is not about you and me.
-肖恩...
-这与你我的事无关
This is about survival.
是生死攸关的事
We need to be somewhere more secure,
somewhere we can stay alive.
我们需要去更安全的地方
一个可以活下去的地方
- We're with you, Shaun.
- What?
-我们跟你走,肖恩
-什么?
- We're with you.
- I'm not going out there.
-我们跟你走
-我才不要出去
Daffs! I don't want to be torn to pieces
and if you think about it, neither do you.
大卫! 我不想被分尸
你若考虑过,你也不愿那样的
- I'm not going if Lizzie's not going.
- She's going.
-如果小丽不走,我也不走
-她会走的
- I'm not staying by myself.
- You're going, aren't you?
-我不要一个人留下来
-你要走,是不是?
- Lizzie?
- Liz?
-小丽?
-丽兹?
- All right, Flash, what's your plan?
- Great. I've got a car
-好吧,简单说说你的计划为何?
-太好了,我有辆车
but it's gonna be a bit cramped now.
Has anyone got transport?
不过现在呢有点挤,还有人有车吗?
- Yes!
- Great. Where?
-有的!
-太好了,在哪?
Oh, no. Well, I've passed my test.
哦,不是! 我考到驾照了
David?
大卫?
I don't see the point
of owning a car in London.
我觉得在伦敦买车来开没什么用
Look, just get any blunt objects together.
听着,拿任何钝器都行
If you get cornered,
bash them in the head.
如果被围住,朝头部用力敲下去
Keep together, stay sharp and follow me.
聚在一起,保持警觉并跟着我走
So, what's the plan, then?
那计划到底为何?
We're going to the Winchester.
我们要去温彻斯特
OK? Let's go.
好了吗? 我们走
- Come on.
- Where's the car?
-快点
-车子呢?
What's up, niggaz?
怎么了,混混?
Apologies for the cramped conditions.
Di, stay on David's lap.
很抱歉里头满挤的
小黛,坐在大卫的膝盖上
Philip, hang in there, OK?
Ed, get there fast.
菲利普,撑着点好吗?
艾德,开快点
And, Mum, this is Liz. Liz, Mum.
妈,这是丽兹! 丽兹,这是妈
Hello.
你好
Ed, be careful.
艾德,小心点
- Is your dad all right?
- He's not my dad.
-你爸没事吧?
-他不是我爸
- He's bleeding.
- I know! Ed, be careful.
-他在流血呢
-我知道! 艾德,小心开车
Thought you wanted to get there fast?
你不是说要开快点吗?
I want to get there in one piece!
Why are we going this way?
我想整个人好好的到达那里!
干嘛走这条路?
Chill out, it's a short cut.
别紧张,这是捷径
- That road goes to the Winchester.
- Shaun...
-那条路通往温彻斯特
-肖恩...
- Liz, please!
- I don't understand why the Winchester?
-丽兹,麻烦一下!
-我还是不懂干嘛非要去温彻斯特?
- It's a pub, it's safe, it's secure.
- They know us.
-那是个酒吧,那里安全
-他们认识我们
- What makes it so secure?
- It's got big heavy doors and deadbolts.
-酒吧为何会安全?
-因为有厚重的大门和门闩锁
And there's a rifle above the bar.
而且酒吧上方有把莱福枪
- I would think that's deactivated.
- It's not. John's connected. Big Al says so.
-我想那把枪不能击发了
-才没呢! 约翰有关连,大艾尔说的
Big Al also says dogs can't look up.
大艾尔也说狗不会辨识颜色
- They can't.
- Can't they?
-们不会
-会吗?
- Of course they can!
- Are you sure?
-当然会!
-你确定?
Yes! The pub is the right place to go.
Everything is gonna be fine.
是的! 这酒吧是最好的去处
一切会没事的,我保证
- Shaun...
- I turned it off, all right?
-肖恩...
-已经关掉了,好吗?
What?
什么?
- Being a father, it's not easy.
- What?
-当个父亲并不容易
-什么?
You were 12 when I met you,
you'd already grown up so much.
你碰到你时,你那时才12岁
就已经长的很大了
I just wanted you to be strong
and not give up because you lost your dad.
我只是希望你能坚强起来
别自暴自弃,因为你刚失去了父亲
- Philip, you don't have to explain.
- No, I do. I always loved you, Shaun.
-菲利普,你不必解释
-不,我要,我一直很爱你,肖恩
And I always thought
you had it in you to do well.
我一直认为你很有潜能
You just need...m-motivation.
你只是需要点...激励
Somebody to look up to and...
一个可以做为榜样的人,以及...
I thought it could be me.
我以为那个人会是我
Would you just...take care of your mum?
好好照顾你妈...好吗?
There's a good boy.
这样才乖
- Ed, can you pull over?
- Two seconds.
-艾德,靠边停一下
-等一下
- Ah! Ed, please pull over.
- What for?
-艾德,麻烦靠边停
-为什么?
- Just pull over!
- All right.
-靠边停就是!
-好啦
Whoa, momma!
哇,妈妈!
- What the hell are you doing?
- Chill out. Everyone's all right.
-你究竟在搞啥鬼呀?
-冷静点,大家都很好啊
Stop telling me to chill out!
少叫我冷静!
- And everybody is not all right.
- What's wrong?
-大家才不好呢
-怎么了?
Mum, it's Philip, he's gone.
妈,菲利普去了
- Where's he gone?
- Mum, he's dead.
-他去哪了?
-妈,他死了
No, he isn't.
不,他才没呢
Get out!
下车!
Jesus!
老天!
- Get it open!
- Ed, get the child locks!
-快打开!
-艾德,打开幼童安全锁!
Quick!
快!
- The child lock!
- Ed!
-幼童安全锁!
-艾德!
- Now what?
- We keep moving.
-现在怎么办?
-我们继续前进
- How do we get Philip out the car?
- We haven't got time.
-怎样把菲利普弄出车外?
-没时间了
- We can't leave your dad.
- He's not my dad!
-不能这样丢下你爸
-他不是我爸!
Mum, he was, but he's not any more.
妈,他过去是,不过现在不是了
- I really think we could...
- That's not your husband in there. OK?
-我真的觉得我们可以...
-里头那个不是你老公,懂吗?
It looks like him but there is nothing
of the man you loved in that car.
虽然外表像他,可是已经完全不是
你所爱的那个男人了
Let's go, shall we?
可以走了吗?
You're not suggesting we walk?
你不会是建议我们用走的吧?
- Everybody OK?
- Yeah, we're having a whale of a time.
-大家没事吧?
-嗯,我们时间多的很
Maybe we should all hold hands,
make a crocodile?
也许我们全该手牵手,连成一线?
Do you know where we're going?
你知道我们走去哪吗?
- David, come on.
- Sorry.
-大卫,别这样
-对不起
- Do you, though?
- Yeah, totally.
-你知道吗?
-嗯,清楚的很
Are we close?
快到了吗?
We're pretty close.
非常接近了
- Is your mum gonna be OK?
- Yeah, I hope so.
-你妈不要紧吧?
-嗯,希望如此
- Did you contact your folks?
- They're in Antigua.
-你连络过你的家人吗?
-他们在安地瓜
- Do you think this is happening there?
- I hope not.
-你认为那里也有发生这种事吗?
-希望没有
About last night.
I know loads of things were said but...
关于昨晚的事
我知道我说了一大堆,不过...
- You said this wasn't about us.
- No, it's not.
-你说这与我们的事无关
-是,的确无关
- You said it was about survival.
- It is, but...
-你说是生死攸关的事
-是没错,不过...
You're not just trying to prove something?
I meant everything I said last night.
你不是想证明什么吧?
我指昨晚我说的话
- Maybe this isn't the best time to talk.
- OK.
-也许现在不是谈话最佳时机
-好的
Shaun.
肖恩
Yvonne.
冯妮
- How's it going?
- Er, surviving.
-你怎样?
-还活着
Hey, Liz. Long time no see.
嘿,丽兹,好久不见
Hey, Yvonne.
嘿,冯妮
Erm...this is my boyfriend, Declan.
嗯...这是我男朋友狄克兰
Erm...my friends Mark, Maggie,
嗯...我朋友马克和梅姬
- my mum and my cousin Tom.
- All right.
-我妈和我堂弟汤姆
-好了
This is Shaun and his girlfriend Liz.
这是肖恩和他的女朋友丽兹
- They've split up, actually.
- Oh, really?
-其实他们已经分手了
-哦,真的吗?
- Yeah.
- That's a shame.
-对
-真可惜
We should scoot.
Have you got somewhere you're going?
我们该走了,你们有要去什么地方吗?
- Yeah, we're going to the Winchester.
- The pub?
-有,我们要去温彻斯特
-酒吧?
- Yeah.
- Right, well. Good luck!
-对
-好吧,祝你们好运了!
Hi.
嗨
Hello.
哈
Hi.
嗨
Hello.
哈
All right.
好了
See? The Winchester's just over there.
看见没? 温彻斯特就在那边
- Over where?
- Over there.
-哪边?
-那边
Just over there, over the 20 garden fences?
就在那边,穿过二十个花园围墙吧?
What's the matter, David?
你有病呀,大卫?
Never taken a short cut before?
以前没走过捷径吗?
Shaun.
肖恩
I'm sure Jill and Derek live round here.
我确定吉儿和德瑞克住这附近
Now, the Winchester
is just over that fence, all right?
过了那围墙就是温彻斯特,好吗?
Everyone stay where they are, I'll...
Are we all here?
大家留在原地,我要...
人都到齐了吗?
- One, two, three, four, five. Yes.
- There's six of us.
-一、二、三、四、五,到齐了
-我们有六个人
Mum!
妈!
I'm coming!
我来了!
Mum, are you OK? Are you OK?
妈,你没事吧? 没事吧?
I don't think Jill and Derek do live here.
我想吉儿和德瑞克不住这里
Shaun?
肖恩?
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
Shaun!
肖恩!
Yes!
好极了!
No, that's rubbish.
不,一点用也没
- Ooh!
- Yes!
哇塞!
Feel free to step in any time.
欢迎随时进来
- You did all right.
- I didn't want to cramp your style.
-你做的不错
-我才不想学你那样
I'm so sorry about that.
刚才的事我很抱歉
Right.
好
OK, everyone stay where they are.
I'm gonna check if the coast is clear.
好,大家留在原地
我检查一下路面安全了没
- Is it clear?
- No.
-安全了吗?
-没有
- How many?
- Lots.
-有多少?
-多的要命
Oh, well, that is just great.
哦,真是好极了
There are a fair few of them, yes.
外头好多呢
I trust Shaun has another genius scheme
up his sleeve?
我竟然相信肖恩还会有高明过人的对策?
This is hardly constructive, David!
这话一点建设性也没,大卫!
- We should have stayed at the flat.
- Why didn't you?
-我们早该留在公寓里
-那你为何没留在那里?
Because... Because, because of...
Captain Wow.
因为...因为,因为...哇队长
- Will you stop it?
- We'll get nowhere moaning.
-你住嘴行吗?
-放马后炮也于事无补
Right, let's all shake out.
Get nice and limber.
好,我们抖抖双手,活动一下筋骨
Or not.
或者免了
Take another look at the way he moves.
Remember, very limp.
再看一遍他的动作
记住,要非常蹒跚
Almost like sleepwalking. Look at the face,
it's vacant with a hint of sadness.
差不多像梦游一样,看看脸部
眼神空洞带点悲伤味道
Like a drunk who's lost a bet.
就像赌输了的酒鬼
OK, let's try, shall we? Liz.
好,来试试看吧? 丽兹
Nice. Good vocal work.
OK. Barbara, that's excellent.
不错,声音做的不错
好的,芭芭拉,那表情太棒了
Sorry, dear, I was miles away.
抱歉,亲爱的,我刚刚分神了
- D-Daffs.
- Uh.
大卫
- Come on!
- Urgh.
-快点!
-呃
It's mournful, sorrowful,
you're dead and you hate it. Go.
带点呻吟、悲伤
你死了而且你讨厌那样,开始
Uuurgh.
呃
- Much better. Ed.
- I'll do it on the night.
-好多了,艾德换你
-我晚上才会做
This is the night!
现在就是晚上!
- What is that?
- What about yours?
-那是啥呀?
-那你呢?
Who died and made you
fucking king of the zombies?
谁死了让你变成该死的僵尸王?
Don't...
别...
Yeah, that's pretty good.
嗯,那样很棒
Right, let's all try together, shall we?
One, two, three.
好,大家一起来试试看,好吗?
一、二、三
Go, go, go, go.
快,快,快,快
Shit! Get round me, get round me!
该死! 围住我,围住我!
John? John, Bernie, are you there?
It's Shaun and Ed. We come in all the time.
约翰? 约翰、柏妮,你们在吗?
是肖恩和艾德,我们常来的
- They can hear you.
- We do the quiz.
-他们听见你了
-我们有问题了
- They know.
- Stay in character!
-他们晓得了
-继续装死人样!
- I can't see them.
- Shaun, we have to get inside.
-我看不见他们
-肖恩,我们必须进去
- Break the window.
- We'll be exposed!
-破窗而入
-我们会曝光的!
- Break the window!
- Is there another way in?
-打破窗子!
-还有别的路进去吗?
Yeah, there's...
嗯,有个...
Two seconds. Hey, Noodle.
等我一下! 嘿,面条
- 'All right?'
- Yeah, man, I can't talk now.
-好了吗?
-老兄,我现在不方便讲话
- 'You get anything yet?'
- I got nothing.
-拿到货了吗?
-没有
I'm in the middle of something.
Yeah, it's weird.
我现在有事在忙,对,很奇怪
- Oi! What are you doing?
- What are you doing? You stupid moron.
-噢! 你在干嘛呀?
-你在干嘛? 超级大白痴
- Fuck off.
- You fuck off!
-滚开
-你才滚开!
Fuck fucking off! I've spent an entire life...
该死的滚开! 我这辈子都在...
Look at me. I've spent my entire life
sticking up for you
看着我! 我这辈子都在支持袒护你
and all you ever do is fuck things up
and make me look stupid.
你却只会把事情搞砸,令我难堪
I'm not gonna let you do it any more.
Not today!
我不会再让你这样了
今天不行!
Shaun.
肖恩
Oh.
哦
You were saying about another way in?
你刚说还有别的路进去?
Yeah, there's a...
对,有条...
What are you doing?
你在干嘛呀?
- No!
- Get inside.
-不!
-进去
No, they'll follow us.
Keep up the act, I'll have to do something.
不行,他们会跟我们进去的
继续表演,我得想个办法
- What do you mean do something?
- Hello, hello, over here!
-你说想办法是什么意思?
-喂,喂,这边!
Come on, that's it.
Come on, that's it, over here!
快点,这就对了
快点,就是这样,靠过来!
Over here! Come on. Oh, bollocks.
这边! 快点! 哦,混帐东西
- Wait till I've gone then get inside.
- Gone where?
-等我走了再进去
-走去哪?
I won't be long, I promise. Come on,
you pasty-faced fuckers, let's go! Follow me.
不会很久的,我保证
来吧,你们这些行尸走肉,我们走! 跟我来
Come on, this way, that's it!
快点,这边,没错!
Come on. This way, follow me.
Come on, follow me.
快点,这边,跟我来
快点,跟我来
Come and get it. It's a running buffet.
来抓呀,流动餐车唷
All you can eat!
通通随你们吃!
Shall we go in, then?
可以进去了吗?
- Come on, Barbara. Leave those.
- I think they're for me.
-快点,芭芭拉,别管那些花了
-我想花是要送我的
- He's been gone a good 20 minutes.
- 17.
-他已经去了20分钟了
-17分钟
Either way, we need to think about blocking
up this window. We're totally exposed.
没差啦,我们必须考虑堵住窗户
我们完全曝光
- How will Shaun get back in?
- I'm sure he'll knock.
-肖恩要怎样进来?
-我相信他会敲门的
- Let's get some lights on.
- David, wait!
-开点灯吧
-大卫,等一下!
- Power's off.
- That's a good thing.
-没电
-那是好事
- We mustn't advertise our whereabouts.
- No, of course not.
-我们不可曝露我们的所在
-对,当然不行
- Do we, David?
- No, of course not, Lizzie.
-对吗,大卫?
-对,当然不行,小丽
I'm just being proactive.
我只是做好预防准备
There's no lights, no power.
And there's a hole in the window.
没灯光、没电力,窗户还有个破洞
- You did that, you twat.
- Somebody had to do something!
-是你这家伙干的好事
-有些事总得有人去做!
We were in a spot of bother. Somebody
has to take control of the situation
我们身在虎穴,得要有人来控制情况
and if none of you are prepared
to accept that responsibility
如果你们没人准备扛下那重责大任
then perhaps...I should.
那或许...该由我来扛
- Will Shaun be gone long?
- He'll be back soon.
-肖恩会一去不回吗?
-他很快就会回来的
- How do you know?
- I don't think he'd leave us.
-你怎知道?
-我认为他不会丢下我们不管
Wouldn't he? How can you trust a man
you binned for being unreliable?
不会吗? 你怎能信任一个
你觉得不可靠的人呢?
A man whose idea of a romantic nightspot
is also an impenetrable fortress.
一个把浪漫夜总会
当成固若金汤城堡的人
This is a pub! We are in a pub!
What are we going to do?
这是间酒吧! 我们在酒吧里!
我们要做什么?
I could get a round in.
我可以喝一杯
Let's just wait for Shaun. We'll barricade
the window when he gets back.
我们等肖恩回来就是
他一回来,我们就把窗户堵死
What then? How long?
Days? Weeks? A month?
什么时候? 等多久?
几天? 几星期? 一个月?
- What are we going to eat?
- Toasties!
-我们要吃什么?
-土司!
- There's a Breville out back.
- Great. Saved by nibbles.
-后面有间布列维尔
-太好了,靠零嘴救命
Must be why Shaun took us here
before he left.
难怪肖恩离开前先带我们来这里
- He's coming back!
- Why? Because he promised?
-他就快回来了!
-为什么? 因为他保证过吗?
If he does, do you think his master plan
will be anything more than eating peanuts?
真要回来的话,你觉得他的超级计划
除了吃花生会能有什么吗?
Is he just gonna stroll in
and suddenly everything's OK?
还是他只要走进来
突然间一切就没事了?
I don't know, David!
I don't know any more than you do.
我不知道,大卫!
我不比你知道的还多
But what I do know is that we're here now
and we have to make the best of it.
但我知道的是我们现在在此
而我们必须善加利用
- Ed, get me a double vodka.
- Right you are.
-艾德,给我一杯双份伏特加
-没问题
I'll have a drink too.
Would you like a drink, Barbara?
我也要喝一杯
你要吗,芭芭拉?
- Hello.
- Right, great, fuck it.
-哈
-对,好极了,管它的
We'll have a party
and get completely smashed.
我们来开个派对,喝个酩酊大醉
We've got our nibbles.
We've got our Mini Cheddars.
我们有零嘴,有迷你乳酪
- David!
- We got Twiglets. Oh, look, hog lumps.
-大卫!
-我们有鱿鱼丝! 哦,看,猪肉豆干
Pickle!
小捣蛋!
Hello, Mum. You all right?
你好,妈,你没事吧?
- Everybody OK?
- Yeah.
-大家没事吧?
-是的
- Any sign of John and Bernie?
- No.
-有看到约翰和柏妮的踪影吗?
-没有
- Check upstairs?
- It's locked.
-楼上查过没?
-上锁了
- Phones?
- Dead. Same as the power.
-电话呢?
-不通,电力也不通
- OK...
- Nice of you to join us.
-好的...
-很高兴你能归队
Yeah, well, I promised, didn't l?
对,我保证过,不是吗?
How did you lose them?
你怎样摆脱他们的?
I just gave them the slip.
Wasn't difficult. They're not all that.
我只是甩掉他们,不太困难
他们没那么聪明
- Well, how did you get in?
- The back door.
-那你怎样进来的?
-从后门
I tried to tell you
before you smashed the window.
你打破窗户前我就一直想告诉你
But it wasn't me blowing our cover
by arguing with my boyfriend.
但是跟男朋友吵架
破坏我们伪装的人可不是我
- He's not my boyfriend.
- Might be a bit warm, the cooler's off.
-他不是我男朋友
-可能有点温热,冰箱没电了
Thanks, babe.
谢了
So, what's the plan, then?
那计划呢?
Would anyone like a peanut?
有谁想吃花生吗?
Why don't you do your Clyde?
你何不扮演一下克莱德?
Has anyone seen
Every Which Way But Loose?
有人看过电影《永不低头》吗?
Ed does the most amazing
impression of the orang-utan.
艾德模仿红毛猩猩微妙微肖
- No, it's not.
- It is. Come on. Do it.
-不,才不会呢
-会,快点表演吧
- No, no.
- But it's brilliant. Come on.
-不,不
-不过很棒的,快啦
- You've built it up too much.
- No, just do it.
-你说的太夸张了
-不会,只管表演就是
Everyone wants to see it.
We could do with a laugh.
大家都很想看,我们可以开怀一笑
Do it, do it, do it, do it. Come on, do it.
快,快,快,快,快表演吧
I'm not a performing monkey.
我又不是杂耍猴子
- The power's on.
- It's not, I tried it earlier.
-有电了
-不是,我之前试过了
The streetlights are on.
I'll flip the fuses, we can watch television.
街灯亮了
打开保险丝开关就可以看电视了
- What about the lights?
- Yes. Don't advertise our whereabouts.
-那电灯怎么办?
-没错,不可曝露我们的行踪
The lights are on a separate circuit.
Just flip the mains breakers.
电灯是分开来的电路
只要打开主断电器就好
It's quite simple, David.
相当简单,大卫
- Is that it?
- That's it.
-有了吗?
-有了
Liz, erm...have you got a quid?
丽兹...你有铜板吗?
Erm...Yeah.
有的
Never anything on, is there?
根本没节目
What?
怎么?
- I think we might have a bit of a problem.
- What do you mean?
-我想我们可能有点麻烦了
-什么意思?
- They followed me.
- I thought you said you gave them the slip.
-他们跟随了我
-你不是说甩掉他们了吗?
Yeah.
没错
Well, we'll just have to be
extra quiet then, won't we?
那我们只好格外安静点
What?
怎么?
Ed, no!
艾德,不!
Turn it off!
关掉!
Shit!
该死!
- Where the hell did he come from?
- I dunno.
-他到底从哪冒出来的?
-不知道
- Who put this on?
- It's on random.
-谁放这首歌的?
-是随机播放的
Dianne, get Mum somewhere safe.
David, kill the Queen.
黛安,带妈去安全场所
大卫,叫《皇后》别唱了
- What?!
- The jukebox!
-什么?!
-自动点唱机!
- Liz, Ed, grab a weapon.
- What about the rifle?
-丽兹、艾德,去拿武器
-莱福枪怎样?
- Cocktails?
- What do you mean?
-鸡尾酒?
-什么意思?
The flaming spirits
Get a rag in, light it.
燃烧的灵魂
塞点破布,然后点火
- But the whole place could go up.
- What, then?
-但整间屋子可能会着火
-那怎么办?
How about pool?
撞球杆如何?
* Don't stop me now
"此刻别阻止我"
* Don't stop me
"别阻止我"
- * Cos I'm having... *
- John, it's time at the bar.
-"因为我正..."
- 约翰,该棒打老虎了
* I'm a shooting star
leaping through the sky like a tiger
"我是划过天际的流星,宛如猛虎"
* Defying the laws of gravity
"违抗着地心引力"
* I'm a racing car passing by
like Lady Godiva
"我是疾速奔驰的赛车,恰似戈瓦迪夫人"
* I'm gonna go, go, go
"我要冲冲冲"
* There's no stopping me
"无可阻挡我"
* I'm burning through the sky...
"我要燃烧整片天空..."
- I can't find the switches!
- Then get the fuses!
-我找不到开关!
-那就拔掉保险丝!
* That's why they call me Mister Fahrenheit
"所以人们叫我华氏先生"
* I'm travelling at the speed of light
"我以光速穿梭旅行"
* I wanna make
a supersonic man out of you
"要做个令你刮目相看的超音速男子汉"
* Don't stop me now
"此刻别阻止我"
* I'm having such a good time
"我正玩得开心"
* I'm having a ball
"我在舞会狂欢"
* Don't stop me now
"此刻别阻止我"
* If you wanna have a good time
"如果你想开心"
* Just give me a call
"只要来通电话"
* Don't stop me now
cos I'm having a good time
"此刻别阻止我,因为我正玩得开心"
* Don't stop me now
"此刻别阻止我"
* Yes I'm having a good time
I don't wanna stop at all
"是的,我正玩得开心,完全不想停"
- * I'm a rocket ship on my way to Mars...
- Why is Queen still on?
-"我是艘航向火星的火箭船..."
-《皇后》怎还在唱呀?
- We have a situation!
- I know!
-有状况!
-我知道!
- Fuck this. Two seconds.
- Ed!
-去死吧,等我一下
-艾德!
* Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, explode
"哦哦哦...爆炸了"
* I'm burning through the sky, yeah...
"我要燃烧整片天空"
Shaun!
肖恩!
*..call me Mister Fahrenheit...
"...叫我华氏先生..."
No!
不!
Yes! Yes! In the head!
对! 对! 射头!
Shauny!
肖恩!
* Don't stop me
Ooh, ooh, ooh
"别阻止我,哦哦哦"
* Don't stop me, don't stop me
good time, good time
"别阻止我,我阻止我,欢乐时光..."
* Don't stop me... *
"别阻止我..."
Why didn't you just shoot him, man?
你怎不干脆开枪打他?
Ed, for the last time, it's...
艾德,我最后一次...
I fucking knew it!
What did I tell you? Big Al was right.
我就知道!
我怎跟你说的? 大艾尔说的没错
OK.
好吧
But dogs can look up.
不过狗会辨识颜色
- Has anyone fired a gun before?
- Oh, yeah.
-有人之前开过枪吗?
-哦,有的
- Apart from Ed?
- I'm a pacifist.
-除了艾德之外?
-我是和平主义者
- Apart from David and Ed?
- What was Ed's experience?
-除了大卫和艾德之外呢?
-艾德的经验是怎样?
- He shot his sister in the leg.
- I think you should do it.
-他射中他姊的腿
-我想该由你开枪
- We should all do it.
- How can five people operate one gun?
-应该我们全部都要
-五个人怎样操作一把枪?
- No one has any experience. We've got...
- 29.
-没有人经验,我们有...
-29发
- 29 bullets.
- Call them shells.
-29发子弹
-要讲弹药
29 shells. I need someone
to help me reload,
29发弹药,我需要有人帮我上膛
everyone else to look out. I will fire.
其他人警戒,我开枪射击
As Bertrand Russell said the only thing
that will redeem mankind is co-operation.
如同柏崔罗素说过:
“解救人类唯一办法便是互相合作”
I think we can all appreciate that now.
我想我们现在都会感激他说的那句话
- Was that on a beer mat?
- Yeah, it was Guinness Extra Cold.
-啤酒垫上的是什么东西?
-是健力士超冰凉啤酒
- I won't say anything.
- Thanks.
-我没意见
-谢谢
- They want to come in.
- Get Mum out of the way.
-他们想闯进来
-带妈离开
David, Dianne, let's go.
Ed, give me some shells.
大卫、黛安,我们走
艾德,给我一些弹药
- Barbara.
- Oh, hello.
-芭芭拉
-哦,哈
- Would you like to come with me?
- That'd be lovely.
-要跟我来吗?
-好的
It's nice to meet you, finally.
Shaun's always talking about you.
很高兴终于见到你
肖恩一直跟我提起你
- Really?
- Yeah.
-真的?
-没错
- Ah!
- Barbara?
芭芭拉?
Are you all right?
你不要紧吧?
I've got something for you.
我有东西要给你
Shaun's father gave me this.
Shaun's real father, I mean.
肖恩的父亲给我的
我是指肖恩的亲生父亲
- I'd like you to have it.
- Barbara, Shaun and I have...
-希望你收下
-芭芭拉,肖恩跟我已经...
It seems only right.
似乎给你最适合了
I didn't want to say anything.
我不想说出来
I thought Shaun would be worried.
我怕肖恩会担心
Liz!
丽兹!
Here they come!
他们来了!
- Stay behind me!
- There's one!
-躲在我后面!
-那里有一个!
Sorry, we're closed!
抱歉,我们打烊了!
- The safety!
- That happened to me on stage.
-保险栓!
-我拍戏时也碰过这种情形
Cock it!
开枪!
- There!
- Where?
-那边!
-哪边?
Three o'clock!
三点钟方向!
- Oh! Over there again. Quarter to twelve.
- What?
-那边又来了,差一刻12点方向
-什么?
- 11:45!
- Keep it simple!
-11点45分方向!
-讲简单点!
Top left!
左上方!
- Reload.
- I'm on it!
-上膛
-我在上了!
Come on, come on.
快点,快点
Nice shot.
真是神准
OK, David, Dianne,
let's block up this window!
好的,大卫、黛安,把窗户堵住!
Ed, take over a sec.
艾德,接手一下
- What is it? What's wrong?
- Shaun, I'm so sorry.
-什么事? 怎么了?
-肖恩,我很抱歉
- Mum, what's wrong?
- I didn't want to be a bother.
-妈,怎么了?
-我不想成为累赘
- Mum, I don't understand.
- The man in his pyjamas.
-妈,我不懂
-穿睡衣那个男的
I didn't want to say anything,
I thought you'd be upset.
我不想说什么,我以为你会生气
No, you should've said.
不,你早该说的
- Take over a sec.
- What's going on?
-接手一下
-怎么回事?
- What's up?
- What the hell's going on?
-怎么了?
-到底发生什么事?
- Barbara's hurt!
- Just take over a minute.
-芭芭拉受伤了!
-接手一下
Jesus.
老天
I know first aid.
我懂得急救
Just hang on. Mum!
撑下去呀,妈!
- Mum.
- Is she...?
-妈
-她是不是...?
Just hold on, Mum, you're gonna be fine.
撑住呀,妈,你会好起来的
- I never thanked you.
- For what?
-我从未谢过你
-谢什么?
For these. "To a wonderful mum."
这些花! "致了不起的妈"
It's been a funny sort of day, hasn't it?
在这种日子有点可笑,对吧?
Oh, no, no! Mum, come on.
哦,不,不! 妈,别这样
Stop it, stop it, stop it.
别死,别死,别死
Mum. Please don't go.
妈,求你别死
- What are you doing?
- We have to deal with her.
-你在做什么呀?
-我们得解决掉她
- Daffs!
- For Christ's sake!
-大卫!
-看在老天份上!
- She's gonna come back!
- She's not going anywhere.
-她会复活的!
-不准动她
- She'll change.
- She's my mum!
-她会变的
-她是我妈呀!
- She's a zombie.
- Don't say that.
-她是僵尸
-不准那么说
Move aside. I'm gonna count to three.
闪一旁,我数到三
One...
一...
two...
二...
three!
三!
- Don't point that gun at my mum!
- Calm down.
-枪别指着我妈!
-冷静
Don't point that gun at Barbara!
枪别指着芭芭拉!
- Ed, don't exacerbate things!
- What's that mean?
-艾德,别使事情恶化!
-什么意思?
- This isn't exactly fair.
- Here.
-这样根本不公平
-拿去
- Thank you.
- It's OK.
-谢谢
-不客气
Please, can we just stop
and think about this?
拜大家停下来好好想想
Tell him to put the gun down!
叫他把枪放下!
She's gonna change. You know I'm right.
她会变的,你知道我说的对
And when she does, she'll kill all of us.
That's what your ex can't seem to realise.
等她变了之后会杀死我们全部
你的前任男朋友搞不清楚这点
That's what this is about, isn't it?
He doesn't like me!
就是为了这个缘故,是不是?
他不喜欢我!
He's always hated me
and now he wants to shoot my mum.
他一直讨厌我,如今还想开枪打我妈
- She's not...
- You've never thought I was good enough.
-她不是...
-你从来就认为我配不上她
- What?
- We all know you're in love with Liz.
-你在说什么呀?
-我们都知道你爱上了丽兹
- That is not true.
- Yes it is!
-那不是真的
-是真的!
- That is not true.
- Yes it is.
-那不是真的
-是真的!
- What?
- I know you only hung out with me
-什么?
-我知道你跟我拍拖...
to get close to Liz and when she knocked
you back, I was there to pick up the pieces.
只是为了接近丽兹
我只能捡她不要而剩下的破烂
I've come to terms with that, Daffs,
why can't you?
我都可以接受了,大卫,为何你不行?
Lizzie, I want you to know
that my feelings for you...
小丽,我要你明白我对你的感情...
David! There are slightly more
pressing matters at hand here.
大卫! 现在有更加危急的事
- Like "Daffs" pointing a gun at my mum.
- I'm not being unreasonable, "Pickle".
-对,就像“懦夫”拿枪指着我妈
-失去理性的可不是我,“泡菜”
- Christ, she's not dead!
- She's finished.
-老天,她还没死!
-她完了
For a hero, you're quite a hypocrite.
要当英雄,你真够虚伪了
You've gone from
a chartered accountant to Charlton Heston.
你被却尔登希斯顿开除了
特约会计师一职
I'm not a chartered accountant.
我不是特约会计师
- Well, you look like one.
- Yeah.
-你看起来就像
-没错
- I'm a lecturer.
- You're a twat.
-我是个讲师
-你是个不折不扣的白痴
She's not your mum.
In a minute she'll be just another zombie.
她不再是你妈了
她马上就会变成另一具僵尸
- Don't say that.
- We're not using the Z word.
-不准那么说
-我们不用“僵”开头那个字
Please can we just calm the fuck down!
拜他妈的冷静下来!
Now, I can see what David is trying to say...
我明白大卫想说什么...
- Thank you.
- Even if he is being a twat.
-谢谢
-就算他是个白痴
Yep.
对
And, Shaun... Shaun, look at me.
肖恩... 肖恩,看着我
I can't begin to imagine
how hard this must be for you
我无法想像这对你有多难受
but we can't afford to fall apart.
但我们不能再分化下去
Shaun, babe...
肖恩,宝贝...
I know you don't wanna hear this...
我知道你不想听这种话...
You do it.
你来
I'm sorry, Mum.
抱歉了,妈
Do it!
开枪!
Well...I think we're all agreed,
you did the right thing there.
我想我们一致同意你做了正确的事
David, no!
大卫,不!
David!
大卫!
- Right, I'm leaving.
- What?
-好,我要走了
-什么?
- I'm not staying here.
- David, it's suicide.
-我不要待在这里
-大卫,你这是去自杀
- I think you should go.
- We will. We can defend ourselves.
-我觉得你该走
-我们会的,我们懂得自我防御
- What do you mean "we"?
- What do you mean?
-你是指"我们"吗?
-什么意思?
Opening that door now
would be a very silly thing to do.
现在打开那扇门会是非常愚蠢的行为
- You gonna stay here with him?
- Look...
-你想留下来陪他吗?
-听着...
- After where he led us?
- Let me finish!
-在他带我们来这儿后还想吗?
-让我把话说完!
Shaun didn't ask you to come here.
You came for the same reason I did.
肖恩并没要求你来
你来的理由跟我是一样的
- Get away from that door this instant!
- But...
-马上离那扇门远一点!
-可是...
David!
大卫!
I'm so sorry, Dianne.
我很抱歉,黛安
Maybe I'm not the one
you should be apologising to.
也许你该道歉的人不是我
Shaun...
肖恩...
David! No!
大卫! 不!
No! No! No!
不! 不! 不!
David!
大卫!
- No! No!
- David!
-不! 不!
-大卫!
David!
大卫!
Dianne, no!
黛安,不!
I'm coming, David!
我来了,大卫!
David!
大卫!
Oh dear.
老天
- Cocktails?
- Do it.
-鸡尾酒?
-动手吧
Stay back!
退后!
Shaun, hold them!
肖恩,挡住他们!
Heads!
前面!
- Ed!
- Hurry up!
-艾德!
-快!
Shauny, look who it is.
肖恩,你看谁来了
Fuck-a-doodle-doo!
操他奶奶的!
Ed!
艾德!
- Shaun!
- Ed!
-肖恩!
-艾德!
Don't groan at me, you thick fuck!
少朝我低吼,你这超级混蛋!
I can't hold them!
我挡不住了!
No!
不!
- Shaun!
- Pete!
-肖恩!
-彼得!
I said leave him alone!
我说放过他!
Ed. Ed!
艾德,艾德!
Shaun, bar!
肖恩,进吧!
Ed!
艾德!
What?
什么事?
Chuck us a cloth, will you?
给我一块布,好吗?
- Where are the shells?
- They're on the bar.
-弹药呢?
-在吧上
Oh, fuck.
哦,干
Fuck it!
干!
What are we gonna do?
Where are we gonna go?
我们怎么办? 要去哪呀?
- The cellar.
- Maybe we can get out!
-地下室
-也许我们能逃出去!
- There's a hatch out on to the street.
- You mean go back outside?
-有升降装置通到外面街道
-你是说回外面去?
Oh, give us a fucking break!
哦,他妈的饶了我们吧!
Go!
走!
I can see the street.
我可以看到街道
Come on.
快点
Come on!
快点!
Why won't it open?
怎么打不开呀?
That's it then, we're trapped.
"Hey, let's go to the Winchester!"
就这样了,我们被困住了
“嘿,我们去温彻斯特吧!”
Whose fucking idea was that?
那是谁该死的主意啊?
Man, I've really ballsed this up.
我真的搞砸了
- No, you haven't.
- I have, Liz. I couldn't save us.
-不,你没有
-我有,丽兹,我救不了我们
I couldn't save Di or David.
I couldn't even save Mum. I'm useless.
我救不了小黛或大卫
甚至救不了我妈,我真没用
You shouldn't feel so responsible, you tried.
You did something, that's what counts.
你不该这么自责,你试过了
你尽了力,那点才重要
Yeah, I suppose.
大概吧
Do you think they'll get through?
你想他们会进来吗?
Yeah.
是的
How many shells have we got left?
还剩多少弹药?
Erm...two.
嗯...两发
I suppose we could take a few of them out
if they stand in a line.
我想如果他们排成一排的话
可以解决掉好几个
I wasn't thinking about them.
我不是在想他们
I know.
我知道
- What about Ed? There's only two shells.
- I don't mind being eaten.
-艾德怎么办? 只剩两发弹药
-我不介意被吃掉
How are we gonna do this?
我们要怎样做?
I don't know. Erm...
不清楚...
One of us has to go first.
我们其中一人必须先死
One should do the other
and then do themselves.
一个人射另一个人,然后再对付他们
You should do me.
I'll muck it up if I have to do myself.
该由你来射我
要我自己来的话我会失败的
I don't think I've got it in me
to shoot my flatmate,
我不想在同一个晚上...
my mum and my girlfriend
all in the same evening.
射杀我的室友、我妈和我女朋友
What makes you think I've taken you back?
你怎会认为我又接纳你了?
Well...
嗯...
you don't want to die single, do you?
你不想死了还是单身吧?
Actually...I would like to be shot.
事实上...我愿意被开枪打死
Besides, I've changed. I haven't had a fag
since yesterday, I promise.
此外,我变了,我从昨天起
就没抽过一根菸,我保证
He hasn't.
他没抽
Maybe we should have one now.
也许我们现在该抽一根
- You left them in my flat.
- Yeah, in the bin.
-你留在我公寓的
-对,我丢掉的
- I was desperate.
- Sneaky monkey.
-我当时心情很差
-死猴子
- Sorry.
- I won't say anything.
-抱歉
-没关系
Come on, we're getting out of here.
快点,我们要离开了
- I might just stay here.
- But we can get out.
-我只想待在这里
-但我们出的去了
- You two should make a go of it.
- What are you talking about?
-你们俩应该离开
-你在说什么呀?
- I only hold you back.
- Yeah, but...
-我只会拖累你
-对,不过...
Maybe you should have this.
也许枪该留给你
- Don't you want it?
- No.
-你不要吗?
-不要
I can't hit anything with it anyway,
I'm rubbish.
反正我也打不中,我枪法太烂了
- Ed, I'm sorry.
- What for?
-艾德,对不起
-为什么?
- Cos I was shouting at you earlier on.
- It's all right.
-因为我稍早前对你大吼大叫
-没关系
I'm sorry too.
我也很对不起
It's OK.
不要紧了
No...
不...
I'm sorry, Shaun.
对不起,肖恩
Oh, God! That's not funny.
老天! 不好玩
- I'll stop doing 'em when you stop laughing.
- I'm not laughing.
-你不笑我就不会这样做了
-我没在笑
You'd better be off.
你们最好快走
Bye, Ed. Love you.
拜,艾德,爱你
Cheers.
加油
I love you too, man.
我也爱你,老弟
Gay.
玻璃
- Ready?
- Ready.
-准备好了吗?
-准备好了
Section One. Ready.
一区准备好
Zombies to your front. Fire!
朝正前方僵尸,射击!
Fire!
射击!
Oh, my God! Shaun!
老天! 肖恩!
Yvonne?
冯妮?
- How are you doing?
- Surviving.
-你们怎样?
-还活着
They're taking us somewhere safe.
I thought you two might want to tag along.
他们要带我们去安全地方
我想你们两个可能想一块去
Is it just the two of you?
就剩你们两个吗?
Well, glad somebody made it.
很高兴还有人活下去
Come on.
来吧
'Next, the story of
ten-year-old Enrique Ramirez
接下来报导现年十岁
安立奎拉米雷兹的经历
'who fought off the reanimated corpses
of his entire family.
独力击败全家人复活的僵尸
'It's all coming right up on
Zombies From Hell.'
都在即将播映的
《地狱来的僵尸》节目中
'Six months on and, to many, the events
of Z-Day must seem like a bad dream.
对许多人来说,六个月来的僵尸事件
必定仿佛一场恶梦
'As we now know, the phenomenon
resulted from the use of...'
我们现在得知,该现象起源于...
'..not something I ever expected as
a newscaster to have to say on air.
..不像是身为新闻播报员的我
曾料想的到会报导出来的事
"'Removing the head
or destroying the brain." Incredible.'
“砍掉头部或摧毁脑部”,太不可思议了
'..to have a top band with us, talking about
their work for the charity Zombaid...'
..我们请到当红乐团来谈谈他们
对于帮助僵尸慈善活动工作的看法...
'The fact that the mobile deceased
retained their primal instincts
事实上这些僵尸
依然保有他们的原始本能
'make them ideal recruitment
for the service industry,
使他们成为服务业的理想新员工
'as well as other roles such as...'
就好比其他人的角色,譬如...
'He can't quite get it.
Ooh! He's fallen, he's down!'
他抓不到! 哦! 他摔倒滑下去了!
'I don't see nothing wrong with it
but I know that some people would.
我是不觉得怎样
不过我知道有些人可能会
'But he's my husband, you know.
I still love him and I got the ring.
但他是我丈夫,你知道的
我仍然爱他,戒指也还戴在手上
- 'You go to bed with it?'
- 'Course I do.'
-你还跟它一块睡?
-当然了
'People can't understand
why she's with him?'
人们不懂为何她还跟他住在一起?
'Initial claims that the virus was caused by
infected monkeys have been dismissed...'
初期宣称病毒是由受到感染的猴子
所导致的说法已经遭到驳斥...
Hello.
哈
What's the plan, then?
有何计划?
Right, a cup of tea...
对,喝杯茶...
then we get the Sundays.
然后买张《周日乐团》的唱片
Head down the Phoenix for a roast,
再开车到凤凰城去吃个烤肉大餐
veg out in the pub for a bit
到酒吧里呆坐一会儿
then wander home,
watch a bit of telly, go to bed.
然后再逛回家,看点电视,上床
- Perfik.
- I'll get the kettle on.
-完美
-我去烧开水
- Can I have two sugars, please?
- Ooh! Adventurous.
-麻烦加两颗糖
-哦! 大胆哟
- I might pop into the garden for a bit.
- Go on, then.
-我想到花园里走走
-那就去吧
Two seconds.
一下子就好
'Player two has entered the game.'
玩家二已进入游戏
Ed!
艾德!
Yes!
好耶!
* Ooh, you make me live
"哦,你让我活下去"
* Whatever this world can give to me
"不管世界能给我什么"
* It's you, you're all I see
"是你,我眼中只有你"
* Ooh, you make me live now, honey
"哦,你让我现在活下去,甜心"
* Ooh, you make me live
"哦,你让我活下去"
* Oh, you're the best friend
that I ever had
"哦,你是我有史以来最好的朋友"
* I've been with you such a long time
"我们在一起了好长一段时间"
* You're my sunshine
"你是我的阳光"
* And I want you to know
that my feelings are true
"我要你明白我的真心真意"
* I really love you
"我真的爱你"
* Oh, you're my best friend
"哦,你是我最好的朋友"
* Ooh, you make me live
"哦,你让我活下去"
* Ooh, I've been wandering round
"哦,我一直四处游荡"
* But I still come back to you
* Come back to you
"但我依然回到你身边..."
* In rain or shine
you've stood by me, girl
"不论阴晴圆缺,你始终站在身旁,女孩"
* I'm happy at home
* Happy at home
"我很高兴在家..."
* You're my best friend
"你是我最好的朋友"
* Ooh, you make me live
* Ooh
"哦,你让我活下去"
* Ooh, you're my best friend *
"哦,你是我最好的朋友"
* I was so tired of being upset
"我厌倦了生气"
* Always wanted something
I never could get
"总想要我得不到的东西"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* But I don't know what it is
"但我不清楚为何"
* Everybody's happy nowadays
"如今人人快乐"
* I was so tired of being upset
"我厌倦了生气"
* Always wanted something
I never could get
"总想要我得不到的东西"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* But I don't know what it is cos
"但我不清楚为何,因为..."
* Everybody's happy nowadays
"如今人人快乐"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* But I don't know what it is
"但我不清楚为何"
* Everybody's saying things to me
"人人对我说长论短"
* But I know it's OK, OK
"但我知道没关系,没关系"
* Everybody's happy nowadays
"如今人人快乐"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
life's an illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
life's the illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
life's an illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* Life's an illusion, love is a dream
life's an illusion, love is a dream
"人生如同幻影,爱情有如梦境"
* Everybody's happy nowadays
"如今人人快乐"
* Days
"快乐日子"
* Bet you are tired of being upset
"我敢说你厌倦了生气"
* Always wanted something
you never could get
"总想要你得不到的东西"
* Life's no illusion, love's not a dream
"人生绝非幻影,爱情亦非梦境"
* Now I know just what it is
"如今我明白为何"
* Everybody's happy nowadays
"如今人人快乐"
* Days *
"快乐日子"